{"posts":[{"intent":"assignments","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"lab classes","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"week 01 input/output functions","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hello where can we find the tutorial solusion","answers":[{"text":"the tutorial questions are replaced by new version with solutions early in the week after the questions are looked at in the tute. go back to tutorials gt week 01 and you should find the questions plus answers.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"assignments","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"lab classes","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"week 01 input/output functions","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"i have just completed first weeks labs but i am not able to access the quiz. sorry for the inconvienience.","answers":[{"text":"i can't see any reason why you shouldn't be able to access it. there's a link to quiz 2 in the right-hand sidebar on the course homepage. this link only becomes visible when you log in.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"assignments","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"lab classes","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"week 01 input/output functions","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"is it possible to get a due date extension arrived in sydney late last night just need a day or two to catch up on all the lectures quiz and lab exercises. understandable if not","answers":[{"text":"do them asap. and let me know when done.","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"i have just completed first weeks labs but i am not able to access the quiz. sorry for the inconvienience.","theta":1,"count":0}],{"text":"also could you provide some instructions for home computing what are mips and spim should i be worrying about this now or will it pop up in future lectures or will week 1 lectures cover this all thanks.","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"home computing varies a little depending on your operating system. there's some instructions here https //taggi.cse.unsw.edu.au/faq/accessing_your_files/ mips is assembly programming. we'll start it in a few weeks you don't need to worry too much about it yet and you will learn how to do it in lectures and labs.","theta":1,"count":0}],[{"text":"i think you can find some info about spim under the documentation tab.","theta":1,"count":0}]]},{"intent":"assignments","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"lab classes","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"week 01 input/output functions","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"are bonus marks arbitrary for each tutor or only assignable in the case of challenge exercises ie is it possible to get bonus marks for this weeks lab","answers":[{"text":"marks are never arbitrary . it's possible to get an a for the week 01 lab. the wording says must complete any challenges if there are no challenges you have to do something well beyond what the lab was asking and discover something interesting. e.g. for this week's lab investigate and explain with empirical results the differences between the various approaches.","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"how do we show to you that we have done something interesting is it through our blogs","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"amaze your tutor when you demo your program in the lab as you are required to do. or at least you're require to demo ... not necessarily amaze.","theta":1,"count":0}]],[{"text":"thanks","theta":1,"count":0}]]},{"intent":"assignments","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"lab classes","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"week 01 input/output functions","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"i think that the command cs1521/bin/check cat4 is missing from the lab spec. was this a mistake or was it intentional without it we can't autotest cat4.c","answers":[{"text":"why can't you autotest it doesn't the command cs1521/bin/check cat4 work","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"no i meant that it's not mentioned in the lab spec above. we aren't instructed to use it to test our solution which is why i got confused. we are told to use cs1521/bin/check cat1 cs1521/bin/check cat2 and cs1521/bin/check cat3 for questions cat1 cat2 and cat3 respectively but nothing for cat4. the command cs1521/bin/check cat4 once executed works completely fine","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"use your initiative. you should always test your work. there's a tool to test your work. qed i.e. i was assuming that i wouldn't need to tell you do it.","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"alright sir i understand. thank you.","theta":1,"count":0}]]]]},{"intent":"assignments","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"lab classes","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"week 01 input/output functions","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"i don't understand how the test scripts are working with these exercises. when i run the test i get the following z5200681 vx2 /tmp_amd/glass/export/glass/4/z5200681/comp1521/week01/lab$ cs1521/bin/check cat2 running tests on cat2 ... failed test 1 check differences using diff tests/1.exp tests/1.out failed test 2 check differences using diff tests/2.exp tests/2.out failed test 3 check differences using diff tests/3.exp tests/3.out failed test 4 check differences using diff tests/4.exp tests/4.out failed test 5 check differences using diff tests/5.exp tests/5.out failed test 6 check differences using diff tests/6.exp tests/6.out z5200681 vx2 /tmp_amd/glass/export/glass/4/z5200681/comp1521/week01/lab$ diff tests/2.exp tests/2.out 1 2c1 lt a simple file lt with two lines --- gt cannot open source file. exiting z5200681 vx2 /tmp_amd/glass/export/glass/4/z5200681/comp1521/week01/lab$ however if i run my programs specifying input and output files from within the tests folder it seems to run fine z5200681 vx2 /tmp_amd/glass/export/glass/4/z5200681/comp1521/week01/lab$ cat tests/2.exp a simple file with two lines z5200681 vx2 /tmp_amd/glass/export/glass/4/z5200681/comp1521/week01/lab$ cat tests/2.out cat tests/2.out no such file or directory z5200681 vx2 /tmp_amd/glass/export/glass/4/z5200681/comp1521/week01/lab$ ./cat2 tests/2.exp tests/2.out z5200681 vx2 /tmp_amd/glass/export/glass/4/z5200681/comp1521/week01/lab$ cat tests/2.out a simple file with two lines z5200681 vx2 /tmp_amd/glass/export/glass/4/z5200681/comp1521/week01/lab$","answers":[{"text":"i see the issue now. even though the comments in the cat template files imply we are opening files i needed to just use stdin and stdout for cat1 2 and 3","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"assignments","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"lab classes","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"week 01 input/output functions","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi dr. shepherd i have a question in regards to week 1 lab part 3. so we have to write a code that reads the file content to a string with fgets and write into an output with fputs thank you. raymond.","answers":[{"text":"yes.","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"correct. but it doesn't read the entire file content into the string if that's what you meant. it reads line-by-line.","theta":1,"count":0}]]},{"intent":"assignments","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"lab classes","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"week 01 input/output functions","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"can we give multiple submissions or is it a one time only","answers":[{"text":"multiple submissions","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"thank you","theta":1,"count":0}]]},{"intent":"assignments","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"lab classes","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"week 01 input/output functions","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"for the tutorial my tutor said i could get the bonus marks by for example writing more tests and a file to run those tests. but how do i submit this additional file for marking","answers":[{"text":"if you're doing this as a bonus exercise showing your tutor in next week's lab should be fine.","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"ok thanks","theta":1,"count":0}]]},{"intent":"assignments","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"lab classes","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"week 01 input/output functions","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"i'm having trouble submitting this lab. with the give command gs_extract no amp assignmap in spec files login z5115499 class cs1531 classrun error detected while scanning spec files for assignment lab01 last system error no such file or directory using webcms classrun directory /import/ravel/3/cs1521/18s2.work/lab01/thu18-tabla/ does not exist login z5115499 stuid 5115499 class cs1521 last system error no such file or directory in both cases no submission has been made. i'm not so sure if this is an error on my part or if the submitted files goes to the thu18-tabla directory and it doesn't exist yet.","answers":[{"text":"hmmm ... where did that lab come from yes you're right that thu18-tabla wasn't mentioned in any of the give/sms files. i've attempted to hack it for lab01. could you let me know if it now works i'll need to ask ask the give/sms maintainers what the correct fix is.","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"yep your hack works thanks","theta":1,"count":0}],{"text":"if i understand the error correctly it looks like you were trying to give to cs1531 instead of cs1521.","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"ooh nice catch yeah when i using the give command i was giving it to the wrong class but then it should have worked for the webcms.","theta":1,"count":0}]]},{"intent":"assignments","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"lab classes","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"week 01 input/output functions","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"how do i check and confirm that my lab exercises have been submitted i remembered that i did submit my labs as soon as i've finished them during the lab time but under the check submission tab it says classrun no record of any submission for this assignment lab01 i also tried checking the collect submission tab and it says classrun your submission for lab01 not yet marked. so i'm assuming the above sentence means that i did submit but i remembered from 1511 that you can check your lab submission using the grades button between your name and the blog button so i checked there and it was empty. i am really confused can someone clarify thanks so much.","answers":[{"text":"the submissions for the monday 1pm lab ended up in the wrong place. someone had forgotten to set the semester to 18s2 so they all ended up in the 18s1 submission directories i'll move them to the correct place this morning and then hopefully you'll be able to see them.","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"cheers","theta":1,"count":0}]]},{"intent":"assignments","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"lab classes","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"week 01 input/output functions","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"im having trouble downloading the warandpeace.txt the cmd said permission denied .","answers":[{"text":"when i was working from home i had permission denied for trying to store the result in /tmp/wp.out. so basically the command below was not working for me. ./cat1 lt /home/cs1521/web/18s2/labs/week01/warandpeace.txt gt /tmp/wp.out but the next command time ./cat1 lt /home/cs1521/web/18s2/labs/week01/warandpeace.txt gt /dev/null worked for me. also doing a quick search online i found this link https //www.archive.org/stream/warandpeace030164mbp/warandpeace030164mbp_djvu.txt","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"thank you very much your command is correct","theta":1,"count":0}]]},{"intent":"assignments","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"lab classes","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"week 01 input/output functions","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"i'm having trouble getting dcc on my laptop as my package manager cannot find dcc. is it okay if i use gcc","answers":[{"text":"dcc is a python script that andrew taylor wrote so it won't be in any package manager. since it's a wrapper around gcc clang you might be able to get it to work on your laptop by grabbing the python script and whatever else it needs and tweaking it yourself. using gcc is fine. if you can use gdb as well then you won't miss dcc too much. an alternative is to use vlab on your laptop and then you get the full cse environment.","theta":1,"count":0}]}]}